<Publish>
	<!--Id must be set in order to update existed mod. it is not required for publishing mod for the first time-->
	<ModId Value="150863" />
	<!--Name of the mod to display to players-->
	<DisplayName Value="Town Road Lane — Road Markings" />
	<!--Short description of the mod-->
	<ShortDescription Value="Road-marking editor: draw lines and area fills on any intersection, plus automatic edge and parking markings for town roads" />
	<!--Long description of the mod. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
	<LongDescription>
# Town Road Lane — Road Markings

A road-marking editor for intersections plus automatic lane markings for ordinary town roads.

## Marking editor
Click any intersection and draw your own markings:
- **Lines** between anchor dots — solid, dashed (short / normal / long), double solid, and G87 white or yellow styles, with adjustable curvature and per-segment visibility. Dots sit on every lane boundary, on the carriageway edge (including past parking lanes), and in a second "setback" row 8 m before the junction — for the solid no-lane-change stretch in front of the stop line.
- **Area fills** over any polygon you outline — points snap to lane endpoints, kerb corners and line crossings, edges follow line curvature. Junction box (yellow box / waffle), white or yellow hatching, green bike lane, red bus lane, concrete, asphalt patch (needs the separate "G87 Vanilla Asphalt Pavement" mod).
- **Hide vanilla markings** per intersection to start from a clean slate.
- Full in-game panel (English + Russian) and hotkeys: **Ctrl+M** toggle tool, **Y** cycle line style, **A** area mode, **U** cycle area fill.

## Automatic markings
Ordinary city roads with 3 m lanes get proper edge lane markings — the same way highways do — so parking, sidewalks and stops react correctly. Parking lane markings included.

## Known limitations
- **The mod is purely visual.** Markings never affect how vehicles actually drive. To change real lane behavior use the Traffic mod (by krzychu124) — set up lane connections and directions there first, then draw your markings to match. The two mods don't sync automatically.
- Nearly-tangent line contacts (well under ~8°) are treated as a graze rather than a crossing — no anchor dot appears at such touch points (by design; prevents jittery duplicate anchors).
- Stretched junction connections (highway ramps/merges and other junctions where the road/junction boundary is not perpendicular to the road) can misplace the anchor dots relative to the painted lines. Fix: normalize the junction with the Node Controller mod so the connection cross-lines run perpendicular to the road — strongly recommended. The setback dot row 8 m before the junction also stays usable.
- After moving or reshaping a road with Move It, line markings adapt to the new geometry, but area fills may not — delete and redraw them.

## Requirements
Both G87 marking packs ship as dependencies and install automatically — they supply the line styles and area fills. Huge thanks to G87 for the marking assets!

---

# Town Road Lane — дорожная разметка

Редактор дорожной разметки для перекрёстков + автоматическая разметка обычных городских дорог.

## Редактор разметки
Кликните по любому перекрёстку и нарисуйте свою разметку:
- **Линии** между точками-якорями — сплошная, пунктир (короткий / обычный / длинный), двойная сплошная, белые и жёлтые стили G87; настраиваемая кривизна и видимость отдельных сегментов. Точки стоят на каждой границе полос, на краю проезжей части (в том числе за парковочными полосами) и вторым рядом за 8 м до перекрёстка — для сплошной перед стоп-линией, запрещающей перестроение.
- **Заливки областей** по обведённому полигону — точки цепляются к концам полос, углам бордюров и пересечениям линий, рёбра повторяют кривизну линий. Вафельная разметка, белая и жёлтая штриховка, зелёная велополоса, красная автобусная полоса, бетон, асфальтовая заплатка (нужен отдельный мод «G87 Vanilla Asphalt Pavement»).
- **Скрытие ванильной разметки** на отдельном перекрёстке, чтобы начать с чистого листа.
- Полноценная панель в игре (английский + русский) и горячие клавиши: **Ctrl+M** — инструмент, **Y** — стиль линии, **A** — режим области, **U** — заливка области.

## Автоматическая разметка
Обычные городские дороги с полосами 3 м получают краевую разметку — как на шоссе, — поэтому парковка, тротуары и остановки работают корректно. Разметка парковочных полос включена.

## Известные ограничения
- **Мод чисто визуальный.** Разметка не влияет на реальное движение машин. Управлять полосами нужно модом Traffic (от krzychu124): сначала настройте там направления и соединения полос, затем нарисуйте разметку под них. Автоматической синхронизации между модами нет.
- Почти касательные контакты линий (заметно меньше ~8°) считаются скольжением, а не пересечением — точка-якорь в таком месте не появляется (намеренно: защита от дрожащих дублей-якорей).
- Вытянутые соединения (съезды и слияния шоссе и другие узлы, где граница «дорога/перекрёсток» не перпендикулярна дороге) могут смещать точки-якоря относительно краски. Лечение: нормализуйте перекрёсток модом Node Controller, чтобы поперечные линии соединений стали перпендикулярны дороге, — настоятельно рекомендуется. Второй ряд точек за 8 м до перекрёстка тоже остаётся пригодным.
- После перемещения или изменения дороги через Move It линии подстраиваются под новую геометрию, а заливки областей — не всегда: удалите их и нарисуйте заново.

## Зависимости
Оба пака разметки G87 подключены как зависимости и ставятся автоматически — они дают стили линий и заливки. Спасибо G87 за ассеты!
	</LongDescription>
	<!--Thumbnail-->
	<Thumbnail Value="Properties/Thumbnail.jpg" />
	<!--Screenshot, can be set multiple times-->
	<!-- Screenshot filenames carry a content hash: the PDX CDN caches by name, so re-publishing
	     under a reused name can serve the stale image. New content = new name, always fresh. -->
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshots/TRL_9f56d721.jpg" />
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshots/TRL_f43d4d3e.jpg" />
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshots/TRL_7f19dcc1.jpg" />
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshots/TRL_332a9cfc.jpg" />
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshots/TRL_a051f879.jpg" />
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshots/TRL_4996f529.jpg" />
	<!--Tag, can be set multiple times-->
	<Tag Value="Code Mod" />
	<!--Link to the forum post where the mod can be discussed-->
	<ForumLink Value="https://forum.paradoxplaza.com/forum/threads/town-road-lane-road-markings-draw-your-own-lines-area-fills-on-any-intersection.1935028/" />
	<!--Version of the mod-->
	<ModVersion Value="2.3.2" />
	<!--Recommended version of the base game to use the mod-->
	<GameVersion Value="1.6.*" />
	<!--Dependency for the mod, can be set multiple times.
	    Both G87 packs supply the render prefabs our styles reference:
	    97828 = [G87] Road Markings (includes UK Set)  - line styles, junction box, bike/bus fills
	    98624 = [G87] Road Markings: Stripes and Chevrons - stripe area fills
	    The mod degrades gracefully without them (vanilla/concrete fallbacks), but every
	    non-default style needs them, so they ship as hard deps for install-and-it-works.-->
	<Dependency Id="97828" />
	<Dependency Id="98624" />
	<!--Required DLC, can be set multiple times. Supported values are "Landmark Buildings", "San Fransisco Set", "Beach Properties", "Urban Promenades", "Modern Architecture"-->
	<RequiredDLC Value="" />
	<!--Change log for new version. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
	<ChangeLog>
# 2.3.2 — settings that stick, markings that stay on the bridge

- **Fixed: mod settings could silently fail to save** (reported as the parking-markings toggle turning itself back on after every game restart). The settings class shared its name with other mods built from the same template, and the game matches settings by bare class name when saving — with such a mod installed, this mod's settings file was never written.
- **Fixed: markings drawn on elevated roads rendered on the ground under the structure.** Anchor dots and area fills on bridges/ramps now sit on the road deck. Area fills drawn on bridges before this update stay on the ground until you hide/show them once (or redraw).
- **Fixed: possible game crash after pressing "Reapply markings" and then editing roads.** The reapply button is removed — refreshing marking prefabs in a live world cannot be made safe. Settings changes now take effect after restarting the game; option descriptions updated accordingly.
- **Fixed: with "Edge line on city roads" disabled, manually drawn lines could stop rendering after loading a save** (with log spam), and in the worst case crash the game. The style prefabs now always exist; the settings toggles only control the automatic markings.
- **Default line curvature now adapts to the connection angle** — a line between diverging ramp lanes gets a default curve that actually hugs the carriageway edge instead of a too-flat one. Existing lines keep their saved curvature.
- Default parking line style is now the G87 dashed decal (falls back to the vanilla dashed line if G87 isn't installed).

# 2.3.1 — fills that survive loading

- **Fixed: some area fills turned invisible after loading a save** (typically the sharp-cornered ones) until toggled hide/show. The game silently re-triangulates every area once the terrain heightmap finishes loading, and shapes its triangulator can't handle lost their fill. The mod now detects that pass and instantly restores its own triangulation.
- **Fixed: fills could slightly overflow their contour after loading** (sawtooth spill past the marking line near sharp tips) — same cause, other half: the game's pass replaced the mod's exact triangulation with its approximate one.
- **Curvature input got −/+ stepper buttons**: click = ±1, Shift+click = ±10, Ctrl+click = ±5.
- Known limitations clarified: on stretched junction connections (highway ramps/merges) misplaced anchor dots are best fixed by normalizing the junction with the Node Controller mod (strongly recommended).

# 2.3.0 — more anchor dots, more styles, calmer UI

- **More anchor dots.** Roads with parking lanes get dots on the true carriageway edge (the outer edge of the parking lane, where the kerb line runs). And every approach now grows a second row of dots 8 m before the junction, following the road's curvature — draw the solid "no lane change" stretch in front of the stop line, or use the row as a workaround on stretched intersections where the cap dots sit awkwardly.
- **4 new line styles:** short dashed, long dashed (highway spacing), G87 yellow solid, G87 yellow dashed.
- **New area fill: Asphalt patch.** Needs the separate "G87 Vanilla Asphalt Pavement" mod (not installed automatically); without it the fill falls back to concrete. Covers markings and sidewalks nicely.
- **Calmer overlay.** The big red crosses at line crossings are now small red dots. Anchor dots stopped pulsing: a free dot is a hollow ring, a dot that already anchors a line is filled with a white core; area-mode candidates use the same ring language.
- A line drawn between two dots of the same lane (setback row → junction) now follows the lane instead of bulging into the intersection.
- **Panel: the Lines and Areas sections fold.** A folded section shows only the row you're working with (expanded, or hovered on the map) — big junctions no longer turn the panel into an endless scroll.

# 2.2.0 — reliable fills, exact contours

- **Fixed: after loading a save, deleting or hiding an area left the fill in the world.** The link between the mod and its spawned fill wasn't persisted, so every save/load cycle silently stacked one more unmanaged copy. Links are now saved with the fill; stray copies accumulated by older saves are detected and cleaned up automatically on load.
- **Fixed: areas could deform after loading a save.** Area anchor points were remembered by list position, and the game reshuffles those lists on every load — editing any marking at such an intersection then snapped the area to wrong points. Anchors now use stable identities that survive save/load; existing areas are migrated automatically and conservatively (an area that can't be safely migrated simply keeps its saved shape until redrawn).
- **The mod now triangulates its own area fills**, bypassing the game's fragile built-in pass. Fills no longer silently vanish on very sharp or very narrow shapes (knife-tip islands, thin medians).
- **Fills follow the exact drawn contour.** Sharp island corners are no longer slightly fattened to survive the game's renderer — the drawing preview and the final fill now match point for point.

# 2.1.0 — curved area fills

Area fills were rebuilt around the sharp curved "islands" between marking lines:
- Area points can now snap to **line crossings**, and area edges **follow the curvature** of the marking line they run along — no more chord-cut polygons.
- Fills no longer silently vanish on areas with very sharp corners (knife-tip islands, medians, gores).
- Areas are no longer auto-split by lines drawn across them: an area is final once drawn, a line over it is purely cosmetic. On load, previously split areas merge back into a single fill (re-check their visibility toggles).
- Fixed: deleting a line reset the visibility/style of every segment at the intersection.
- Fixed: deleting an area could remove the wrong fill and leave a stale one behind.
- UI: style previews in the line/area dropdowns and row headers, reworked on-map popovers (scale with zoom, expand on hover), and two-way hover — point at an area in the panel to highlight it on the map and vice versa.
	</ChangeLog>
	<!--External link, can be set multiple times. supported types are "discord", "github", "youtube", "twitch", "x", "paypal", "patreon", "buymeacoffee", "kofi", "crowdin", "gitlab", "gofundme"-->
	<ExternalLink Type="github" Url="https://github.com/mxerf/town-road-lane" />
	<!--Supported values Public, Private, Unlisted-->
	<AccessLevel Value="Public" />
</Publish>
