<Publish>
	<!--Id must be set in order to update existed mod. it is not required for publishing mod for the first time-->
	<ModId Value="150863" />
	<!--Name of the mod to display to players-->
	<DisplayName Value="Town Road Lane — Road Markings" />
	<!--Short description of the mod-->
	<ShortDescription Value="Road-marking editor: draw lines and area fills on any intersection, plus automatic edge and parking markings for town roads" />
	<!--Long description of the mod. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
	<LongDescription>
# Town Road Lane — Road Markings

A road-marking editor for intersections plus automatic lane markings for ordinary town roads.

## Marking editor
Click any intersection and draw your own markings:
- **Lines** between lane endpoint dots — Solid, Dashed, Double Solid, and G87 line styles, with adjustable curvature and per-segment visibility.
- **Area fills** over any polygon you outline — points snap to lane endpoints, kerb corners and line crossings, edges follow line curvature. Junction box (yellow box / waffle), white or yellow hatching, green bike lane, red bus lane, concrete.
- **Hide vanilla markings** per intersection to start from a clean slate.
- Full in-game panel (English + Russian) and hotkeys: **Ctrl+M** toggle tool, **Y** cycle line style, **A** area mode, **U** cycle area fill.

## Automatic markings
Ordinary city roads with 3 m lanes get proper edge lane markings — the same way highways do — so parking, sidewalks and stops react correctly. Parking lane markings included.

## Known limitations
- **The mod is purely visual.** Markings never affect how vehicles actually drive. To change real lane behavior use the Traffic mod (by krzychu124) — set up lane connections and directions there first, then draw your markings to match. The two mods don't sync automatically.
- Nearly-tangent line contacts (well under ~8°) are treated as a graze rather than a crossing — no anchor dot appears at such touch points (by design; prevents jittery duplicate anchors).
- Non-standard intersections with strongly stretched connections (e.g. reshaped with Node Controller) can misplace the anchor dots. A fix is planned.
- After moving or reshaping a road with Move It, line markings adapt to the new geometry, but area fills may not — delete and redraw them.

## Requirements
Both G87 marking packs ship as dependencies and install automatically — they supply the line styles and area fills. Huge thanks to G87 for the marking assets!

---

# Town Road Lane — дорожная разметка

Редактор дорожной разметки для перекрёстков + автоматическая разметка обычных городских дорог.

## Редактор разметки
Кликните по любому перекрёстку и нарисуйте свою разметку:
- **Линии** между точками полос — сплошная, пунктир, двойная сплошная и стили G87; настраиваемая кривизна и видимость отдельных сегментов.
- **Заливки областей** по обведённому полигону — точки цепляются к концам полос, углам бордюров и пересечениям линий, рёбра повторяют кривизну линий. Вафельная разметка, белая и жёлтая штриховка, зелёная велополоса, красная автобусная полоса, бетон.
- **Скрытие ванильной разметки** на отдельном перекрёстке, чтобы начать с чистого листа.
- Полноценная панель в игре (английский + русский) и горячие клавиши: **Ctrl+M** — инструмент, **Y** — стиль линии, **A** — режим области, **U** — заливка области.

## Автоматическая разметка
Обычные городские дороги с полосами 3 м получают краевую разметку — как на шоссе, — поэтому парковка, тротуары и остановки работают корректно. Разметка парковочных полос включена.

## Известные ограничения
- **Мод чисто визуальный.** Разметка не влияет на реальное движение машин. Управлять полосами нужно модом Traffic (от krzychu124): сначала настройте там направления и соединения полос, затем нарисуйте разметку под них. Автоматической синхронизации между модами нет.
- Почти касательные контакты линий (заметно меньше ~8°) считаются скольжением, а не пересечением — точка-якорь в таком месте не появляется (намеренно: защита от дрожащих дублей-якорей).
- На нестандартных перекрёстках с сильно вытянутыми соединениями (например, после Node Controller) точки-якоря могут располагаться некорректно. Исправление запланировано.
- После перемещения или изменения дороги через Move It линии подстраиваются под новую геометрию, а заливки областей — не всегда: удалите их и нарисуйте заново.

## Зависимости
Оба пака разметки G87 подключены как зависимости и ставятся автоматически — они дают стили линий и заливки. Спасибо G87 за ассеты!
	</LongDescription>
	<!--Thumbnail-->
	<Thumbnail Value="Properties/Thumbnail.jpg" />
	<!--Screenshot, can be set multiple times-->
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshots/Screenshot_04.jpg" />
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshots/Screenshot_01.jpg" />
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshots/Screenshot_02.jpg" />
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshots/Screenshot_03.jpg" />
	<!--Tag, can be set multiple times-->
	<Tag Value="Code Mod" />
	<!--Link to the forum post where the mod can be discussed-->
	<ForumLink Value="" />
	<!--Version of the mod-->
	<ModVersion Value="2.2.0" />
	<!--Recommended version of the base game to use the mod-->
	<GameVersion Value="1.6.*" />
	<!--Dependency for the mod, can be set multiple times.
	    Both G87 packs supply the render prefabs our styles reference:
	    97828 = [G87] Road Markings (includes UK Set)  - line styles, junction box, bike/bus fills
	    98624 = [G87] Road Markings: Stripes and Chevrons - stripe area fills
	    The mod degrades gracefully without them (vanilla/concrete fallbacks), but every
	    non-default style needs them, so they ship as hard deps for install-and-it-works.-->
	<Dependency Id="97828" />
	<Dependency Id="98624" />
	<!--Required DLC, can be set multiple times. Supported values are "Landmark Buildings", "San Fransisco Set", "Beach Properties", "Urban Promenades", "Modern Architecture"-->
	<RequiredDLC Value="" />
	<!--Change log for new version. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
	<ChangeLog>
# 2.2.0 — reliable fills, exact contours

- **Fixed: areas could deform after loading a save.** Area anchor points were remembered by list position, and the game reshuffles those lists on every load — editing any marking at such an intersection then snapped the area to wrong points. Anchors now use stable identities that survive save/load; existing areas are migrated automatically and conservatively (an area that can't be safely migrated simply keeps its saved shape until redrawn).
- **The mod now triangulates its own area fills**, bypassing the game's fragile built-in pass. Fills no longer silently vanish on very sharp or very narrow shapes (knife-tip islands, thin medians).
- **Fills follow the exact drawn contour.** Sharp island corners are no longer slightly fattened to survive the game's renderer — the drawing preview and the final fill now match point for point.

# 2.1.0 — curved area fills

Area fills were rebuilt around the sharp curved "islands" between marking lines:
- Area points can now snap to **line crossings**, and area edges **follow the curvature** of the marking line they run along — no more chord-cut polygons.
- Fills no longer silently vanish on areas with very sharp corners (knife-tip islands, medians, gores).
- Areas are no longer auto-split by lines drawn across them: an area is final once drawn, a line over it is purely cosmetic. On load, previously split areas merge back into a single fill (re-check their visibility toggles).
- Fixed: deleting a line reset the visibility/style of every segment at the intersection.
- Fixed: deleting an area could remove the wrong fill and leave a stale one behind.
- UI: style previews in the line/area dropdowns and row headers, reworked on-map popovers (scale with zoom, expand on hover), and two-way hover — point at an area in the panel to highlight it on the map and vice versa.
	</ChangeLog>
	<!--External link, can be set multiple times. supported types are "discord", "github", "youtube", "twitch", "x", "paypal", "patreon", "buymeacoffee", "kofi", "crowdin", "gitlab", "gofundme"-->
	<ExternalLink Type="github" Url="https://github.com/mxerf/town-road-lane" />
	<!--Supported values Public, Private, Unlisted-->
	<AccessLevel Value="Public" />
</Publish>
