<Publish>
	<!--Id must be set in order to update existed mod. it is not required for publishing mod for the first time-->
	<ModId Value="150863" />
	<!--Name of the mod to display to players-->
	<DisplayName Value="Town Road Lane — Road Markings" />
	<!--Short description of the mod-->
	<ShortDescription Value="Road-marking editor: draw lines and area fills on any intersection, plus automatic edge and parking markings for town roads" />
	<!--Long description of the mod. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
	<LongDescription>
# Town Road Lane — Road Markings

A road-marking editor for intersections plus automatic lane markings for ordinary town roads.

## Marking editor
Click any intersection and draw your own markings:
- **Lines** between anchor dots — solid, dashed (short / normal / long), double solid, G87 white or yellow styles, and a curb line (needs the free "[G87] Vanilla Curb" mod), with adjustable curvature and per-segment visibility. Dots sit on every lane boundary, on the carriageway edge (including past parking lanes), and in a second "setback" row 8 m before the junction — for the solid no-lane-change stretch in front of the stop line.
- **Area fills** over any polygon you outline — points snap to lane endpoints, kerb corners and line crossings, edges follow line curvature. Junction box (yellow box / waffle), white or yellow hatching, green bike lane, red bus lane, concrete, grass, sand, pavement, tiles, asphalt patch (needs the separate "G87 Vanilla Asphalt Pavement" mod).
- **Hide vanilla markings** per intersection to start from a clean slate.
- **Pin favourite styles** — star any entry in a style dropdown to keep it at the top of every list.
- Full in-game panel (English + Russian) and hotkeys: **Ctrl+M** toggle tool, **Y** cycle line style, **A** area mode, **U** cycle area fill.

## Automatic markings
Ordinary city roads with 3 m lanes get proper edge lane markings — the same way highways do — so parking, sidewalks and stops react correctly. Parking lane markings included.

## Known limitations
- **The mod is purely visual.** Markings never affect how vehicles actually drive. To change real lane behavior use the Traffic mod (by krzychu124) — set up lane connections and directions there first, then draw your markings to match. The two mods don't sync automatically.
- **Everything snaps to anchor dots — by design.** The dots sit on real road geometry (lane boundaries, carriageway edges, kerb corners, line crossings, plus the setback row 8 m before the junction), which is why markings land exactly on the lanes in a few clicks. There is no freehand placement: for fully freehand markings place the G87 packs' decals and net-lanes by hand — this mod is the fast-and-precise layer for junctions on top of them.
- Nearly-tangent line contacts (well under ~8°) are treated as a graze rather than a crossing — no anchor dot appears at such touch points (by design; prevents jittery duplicate anchors).
- Stretched junction connections (highway ramps/merges and other junctions where the road/junction boundary is not perpendicular to the road) can misplace the anchor dots relative to the painted lines. Fix: normalize the junction with the Node Controller mod so the connection cross-lines run perpendicular to the road — strongly recommended. The setback dot row 8 m before the junction also stays usable.
- Area fill edges curve along a line only when that line was drawn with this mod. The game's own markings are not traced — along them the fill edge stays a straight segment between its points.
- After moving or reshaping a road with Move It, line markings adapt to the new geometry, but area fills may not — delete and redraw them.

## Requirements
Both G87 marking packs ship as dependencies and install automatically — they supply the line styles and area fills. Huge thanks to G87 for the marking assets!

---

# Town Road Lane — дорожная разметка

Редактор дорожной разметки для перекрёстков + автоматическая разметка обычных городских дорог.

## Редактор разметки
Кликните по любому перекрёстку и нарисуйте свою разметку:
- **Линии** между точками-якорями — сплошная, пунктир (короткий / обычный / длинный), двойная сплошная, белые и жёлтые стили G87, бордюр (нужен бесплатный мод «[G87] Vanilla Curb»); настраиваемая кривизна и видимость отдельных сегментов. Точки стоят на каждой границе полос, на краю проезжей части (в том числе за парковочными полосами) и вторым рядом за 8 м до перекрёстка — для сплошной перед стоп-линией, запрещающей перестроение.
- **Заливки областей** по обведённому полигону — точки цепляются к концам полос, углам бордюров и пересечениям линий, рёбра повторяют кривизну линий. Вафельная разметка, белая и жёлтая штриховка, зелёная велополоса, красная автобусная полоса, бетон, трава, песок, тротуарная плитка, плитка, асфальтовая заплатка (нужен отдельный мод «G87 Vanilla Asphalt Pavement»).
- **Скрытие ванильной разметки** на отдельном перекрёстке, чтобы начать с чистого листа.
- **Пины любимых стилей** — звёздочка в любом дропдауне стилей закрепляет стиль наверху всех списков.
- Полноценная панель в игре (английский + русский) и горячие клавиши: **Ctrl+M** — инструмент, **Y** — стиль линии, **A** — режим области, **U** — заливка области.

## Автоматическая разметка
Обычные городские дороги с полосами 3 м получают краевую разметку — как на шоссе, — поэтому парковка, тротуары и остановки работают корректно. Разметка парковочных полос включена.

## Известные ограничения
- **Мод чисто визуальный.** Разметка не влияет на реальное движение машин. Управлять полосами нужно модом Traffic (от krzychu124): сначала настройте там направления и соединения полос, затем нарисуйте разметку под них. Автоматической синхронизации между модами нет.
- **Всё цепляется к точкам-якорям — намеренно.** Точки стоят на реальной геометрии дороги (границы полос, край проезжей части, углы бордюров, пересечения линий, плюс ряд за 8 м до перекрёстка) — поэтому разметка ложится точно по полосам за несколько кликов. Свободного размещения нет: для полностью ручного рисования ставьте декали и нет-лейны паков G87 вручную — этот мод поверх них как слой «быстро и точно» для перекрёстков.
- Почти касательные контакты линий (заметно меньше ~8°) считаются скольжением, а не пересечением — точка-якорь в таком месте не появляется (намеренно: защита от дрожащих дублей-якорей).
- Вытянутые соединения (съезды и слияния шоссе и другие узлы, где граница «дорога/перекрёсток» не перпендикулярна дороге) могут смещать точки-якоря относительно краски. Лечение: нормализуйте перекрёсток модом Node Controller, чтобы поперечные линии соединений стали перпендикулярны дороге, — настоятельно рекомендуется. Второй ряд точек за 8 м до перекрёстка тоже остаётся пригодным.
- Рёбра заливок изгибаются вдоль линии, только если линия нарисована этим модом. Ванильную разметку заливка не огибает — вдоль неё ребро остаётся прямым отрезком между точками.
- После перемещения или изменения дороги через Move It линии подстраиваются под новую геометрию, а заливки областей — не всегда: удалите их и нарисуйте заново.

## Зависимости
Оба пака разметки G87 подключены как зависимости и ставятся автоматически — они дают стили линий и заливки. Спасибо G87 за ассеты!
	</LongDescription>
	<!--Thumbnail-->
	<Thumbnail Value="Properties/Thumbnail.jpg" />
	<!--Screenshot, can be set multiple times-->
	<!-- Screenshot filenames carry a content hash: the PDX CDN caches by name, so re-publishing
	     under a reused name can serve the stale image. New content = new name, always fresh. -->
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshots/TRL_2ecbc8fe.jpg" />
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshots/TRL_9c1107eb.jpg" />
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshots/TRL_9f56d721.jpg" />
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshots/TRL_f43d4d3e.jpg" />
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshots/TRL_7f19dcc1.jpg" />
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshots/TRL_332a9cfc.jpg" />
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshots/TRL_a051f879.jpg" />
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshots/TRL_4996f529.jpg" />
	<!--Tag, can be set multiple times-->
	<Tag Value="Code Mod" />
	<!--Link to the forum post where the mod can be discussed-->
	<ForumLink Value="https://forum.paradoxplaza.com/forum/threads/town-road-lane-road-markings-draw-your-own-lines-area-fills-on-any-intersection.1935028/" />
	<!--Version of the mod-->
	<ModVersion Value="2.4.0" />
	<!--Recommended version of the base game to use the mod-->
	<GameVersion Value="1.6.*" />
	<!--Dependency for the mod, can be set multiple times.
	    Both G87 packs supply the render prefabs our styles reference:
	    97828 = [G87] Road Markings (includes UK Set)  - line styles, junction box, bike/bus fills
	    98624 = [G87] Road Markings: Stripes and Chevrons - stripe area fills
	    The mod degrades gracefully without them (vanilla/concrete fallbacks), but every
	    non-default style needs them, so they ship as hard deps for install-and-it-works.-->
	<Dependency Id="97828" />
	<Dependency Id="98624" />
	<!--Required DLC, can be set multiple times. Supported values are "Landmark Buildings", "San Fransisco Set", "Beach Properties", "Urban Promenades", "Modern Architecture"-->
	<RequiredDLC Value="" />
	<!--Change log for new version. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
	<ChangeLog>
# 2.4.0 — vanilla surface fills, curb lines, pinned favourites

- **New area fills: the game's own surfaces.** Grass (regular + dark), sand, pavement and three tile styles can now be used as junction fills — no extra mods needed. These vanilla surfaces previously could not render on roads at all; big thanks to the ExtraAssetsImporter source code for showing the way.
- **New line style: Curb.** Draws the vanilla curb texture along any segment — outline traffic islands and medians with a proper curb edge. Needs the free "[G87] Vanilla Curb" mod; without it the style falls back to a plain line.
- **Pin your favourite styles.** Every style dropdown (panel and in-world popovers) now shows a star on each entry — pinned styles stay at the top of every list. Pins persist across game restarts.
- UI: style dropdown menus now size to their longest entry, so nothing clips; fill styles from the auto-installed G87 packs dropped the "(G87)" suffix — the marker stays only on styles that need optional mods (Asphalt — G87 VA, Curb — G87 VC).
- Diagnostics: the startup survey now also logs every net-lane mesh with its dimensions — useful when reporting issues with modded road assets.
	</ChangeLog>
	<!--External link, can be set multiple times. supported types are "discord", "github", "youtube", "twitch", "x", "paypal", "patreon", "buymeacoffee", "kofi", "crowdin", "gitlab", "gofundme"-->
	<ExternalLink Type="github" Url="https://github.com/mxerf/town-road-lane" />
	<!--Supported values Public, Private, Unlisted-->
	<AccessLevel Value="Public" />
</Publish>
